Der Hölle Rache kocht in meinem Herzen,
Hell's vengeance boils in my heart,
Tod! und Verzweiflung,
death! and despair,
Tod und Verzweiflung flammet um mich her!
death and despair blaze about me!
Fühlt nicht durch dich Sarastro Todesschmerzen,
If Sarastro does not feel death's pangs by your hand,
Sarastro Todesschmerzen,
Sarastro's death-pangs,
So bist du meine Tochter nimmermehr
then you are my daughter nevermore
So bist du mein—
then you are my—
meine Tochter nimmermehr—
—daughter, nevermore
♪
Meine Tochter nimmermehr
my daughter, nevermore
♪
So bist du meine Tochter nimmermehr
then you are my daughter nevermore
Verstoßen sei auf ewig, verlassen sei auf ewig,
Be cast out forever, be forsaken forever,
Zertrümmert sei'n auf ewig alle Bande der Natur,
shattered forever be all the bonds of nature,
Verstoßen, verlassen, und zertrümmert—
Cast out, forsaken, and shattered—
alle Bande der Natur, alle Ba—a—
all the bonds of nature, all the bo—o—
a-a-a-a-a-a-a-a-a-a-a-a-
Bande, alle Bande der Natur,
the bonds, all the bonds of nature,
Wenn nicht durch dich Sarastro wird erblassen!
unless by your hand Sarastro grows pale in death!
Hört, Hört, Hört—! Rachegötter!
Hear, hear, hear—! Gods of vengeance!
hört der Mutter Schwur!
hear a mother's oath!